<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: startup | ]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.karekinian.com/blog/categories/startup/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.karekinian.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-10-05T00:54:00+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.karekinian.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://github.com/recurser/jekyll-plugins">Recurser</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Culture]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.karekinian.com/blog/2013/02/21/culture/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-21T09:57:07+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.karekinian.com/blog/2013/02/21/culture</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>At least three insightful articles about culture were posted yesterday. I think you should read them.</p>

<h2><a href="http://37signals.com/svn/posts/3450">When culture turns into policy</a></h2>

<blockquote>
<p>A fine line exists between spelling out company culture and inadvertently
engraving it as policy.</p>

<p>-- Mig Reyes</p>
</blockquote>

<h2><a href="http://blog.prettylittlestatemachine.com/blog/2013/02/20/what-your-culture-really-says/">What Your Culture Really Says</a></h2>

<blockquote>
<p>Culture is not about the furniture in your office. It is not about how much
time you have to spend on feel-good projects. It is not about catered food,
expensive social outings, internal chat tools, your ability to travel all
over the world, or your never-ending self-congratulation.</p>

<p>-- shanley</p>
</blockquote>

<h2><a href="http://ted.io/culture.html">Culture</a></h2>

<blockquote>
<p>In dysfunctional organizations, or, frankly, in organizations where people
are unhappy, &quot;intervention&quot; from other sources (often human resources) is
required because employees don&#39;t actually like the culture, nor do they like
their daily working lives. Entire HR teams are needed to try to convey
supposed organizational culture (often devised ad hoc) to new employees
because natural internal cultural diffusion has failed. At this point, it&#39;s
often too late to authentically fix a culture.</p>

<p>-- Ted Nyman</p>
</blockquote>

<h2><a href="http://37signals.com/svn/posts/1022-you-dont-create-a-culture">You don’t create a culture (from 2008)</a></h2>

<p>It&#39;s linked at the end of Mig Reyes&#39; article but it&#39;s worth a read as well.</p>

<blockquote>
<p>You don’t create a culture. Culture happens. It’s the by-product of
consistent behavior. If you encourage people to share, and you give them the
freedom to share, then sharing will be built into your culture. If you
reward trust then trust will be built into your culture.</p>

<p>-- Jason Fried</p>
</blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
